Hello, my friends.
And welcome to exercise number 11.
We are asked to find the time complexity of this method.
So this function as print hello taking into parametres two arrays to integer arrays, array one and
array A. and array B, the second error and we have inside a two loops nested loops.
OK, and printing.
Hello, I want from you to post a video, write down the solution and check it later on.
When we solve, start solving and compare your progress in that complex time, complexity and big o
notation.
No, that solving like these exercises will help you master this subject in the university and correct
that interview.
OK, so let's begin solving.
We have here.
The void print Hello, IRA.
We don't take care about this.
That we have here the for loop first for Loop is starting from equal to zero and stopping at a rate
at length and a plus a plus.
So we have solved many exercises about this.
This will result in.
Executing the code inside the the outer loop from I equal to zero array, a dot length array ducklings.
I did not it by a.
And we are since we have I + +.
So we are going to go through all elements from zero to a.
OK.
That array length, I will suppose, that a equal to one.
Now, let's go to the inner loop, the inner loop starts off from Jay equal to zero.
Stops at J.
Less than Arab B that length, not that the trick in this question is that we have different array length,
so a array, as may be, would be the length of it less than or equal or greater than array b think.
And we are going to go through all the elements of from zero.
This array.
From zero to I know.
Do not buy B is the length of a recipe.
OK.
And this is for all of what?
So, guys, I will suppose that B is 30.
And eight equal to 20.
If we think about this for a while, if we have 20 times here because the are length is equal to 20.
20 and Bee is 30, so every time we have iteration here above.
Every time I is increased, J or this law, what are they going to print?
Hello.
Thirty times.
OK.
And we have.
Above, we have 20 iterations, so every iteration and outlaw.
It will result in 30 iterations in the end.
Look, this world, if we execute this, if you execute this algorithm inside I.D., we will get 20
times.
For the eye, I iteration times 30, because every time I is executed, there is 30 times executing
and printing hello.
We will get 600 times saying Hello.
System print hello.
We have 600.
Hello.
OK.
I need it from you to think about it.
What would be that time complexity?
If I just before I tell you that notation, in order to solve all the exercises of this time complexity
or space complexity, please go and take example on and change the numbers in order to get the sequence
how this algorithm behaves.
So if I took a equal to 100.
And B is equal to five.
OK.
This will result we are going to loop through the outer loop 100 and each iteration we are going to
print five hello.
So the algorithm here will execute eight times be which 100 times five equals to 500.
Hello.
So we are going to see 500 hello if we change A to 100 and B to five.
Therefore, the complexity of this program is, oh, eight times be OK.
This is the trick in this question.
I denote I like this question because when you see nested loops, many people think about it as an the
square.
And in this case, it's not there in the square.
It is or a square.
It is every.
It is a B because every loop has it's a specific condition, it's specific, limiting and specific way
and behavior.
So the pattern of the loop will detect the correct.